Software Engineer

_

Find me

Phone: +61 459 323 826

Email: pro@yoni-firroloni.com

 $Site: \underline{https://yoni-firroloni.com}$

Github:

https://github.com/vagahbond

_

Education

Master's degree

Software architecture

ESGI, Paris

October 2019 to July 2022

_

Skills

Web:

- NodeJs(TS, React, Svelte)
- Tailwind/Bulma/Material
- HTML/CSS/JS
- Git

Backend:

- Postgres/Mongo
- NestJS
- RabbitMQ/Redis
- Rubv
- C/C++/Rust

DevOps:

- GitHub Action
- Nix
- Kubernetes
- Docker

Yoni FIRROLONI

14 Sorrento Cres, Port Douglas, QLD

Profile

26 years old software engineer, I have been living almost 2 years in Australia on a Working Holiday Visa (417), working as a plant nursery hand and a factory worker.

My New Zealand WHV is already validated and my plane tickets are aquired, with a landing in Auckland on the 4th of November.

With more than 4 years of business experience as both a programer and a CS Bachelor teacher, I would be happy to pick my career back up.

Work experience

Datalok/Software developper

September 2024 until December 2024, Remotely as contractor

Refactor and development of a marketplace for shared datacenter racks.

This position, in a small team included:

- NestJS with typescript
- Stripe
- Docker
- Angular

Keyros/Software developer

August 2020 until Semptember 2023, Saint Mandé (France)

Development of a fullstack web application helping crisis units manage floods of the Seine and other rivers.

In a 3 people team working with agile methods and mostly remotely, included :

- Fullstack development of many features with RoR
- Development and modernization (with TypeScript) of a React frontend
- Gitlab CI pipelines
- Web API with Diango (Python)
- Handling of geographic data with PostgreSQL, ArangoDB(NoSQL), and OpenStreetMap
- Pre-production and production setup, diagnostic and fixes using container images

Keyros won multiple prizes on innovation during this time.

_

Languages:

- ✓ French (Native)
- ✓ English (Fluent)

Personnal projects:

- Self hosted infrastructure using kubernetes and now nix/NixOS (infrastructure-as-code)
- Several projects on audio programming and fingerprinting
- Uni-Verse, a scalable Soundcloud clone

Hobbies and interests:

- Music (Guitar and DAWs)
- Hiking, Climbing, Calisthenics
- Tech watch, personnal dev projects
- Online privacy

Referees

Frédéric Sananes, current educational director at ESGI : fsananes@esgi.fr

Erwan Jossic, current CTO at Keyros :

erwan.jossic@keyros.org

Further references available on request.

ESGI (Private CS uni)/Professor (Contractor)

September 2022 until April 2024, Paris, Nation

Creating material and teaching with it for several topics to +10 groups of ~ 30 students with different specializations.

The material was created in autonomy, from home.

Courses are in a bachelor's degree program and included:

- The C language (beginner and advanced)
- Developing APIs with NodeJS and ExpressJS
- Web Architecture (Apache centered course)
- Web and API (RESTful APIs)
- Introduction to open source development

ESIEE (University)/Assistant Lecturer

September 2023 until January 2024, Noisy-Le-Grand, Nation

Supervising and providing support for assignments and practice sessions for C and C++ courses

H3 HITEMA(Private CS uni)/Professor (Freelance)

March 2023 Issy-les-Moulineaux (France)

Teaching Nodejs development with Typescript, MongoDB, and ExpressJS to a master's degree class.

Newrest Wagons Lits/Apprentice software engineer September 2019 to July 2020, PARIS, 17e

NWL is a subsidiary of Newrest, catering company that has a network of 3,200 employees around the world.

- Retro-engineering an old Oracle ERP to modernize it
- An Android Studio app for the tradespeople to connect their Electronic Payment Terminals
- A backoffice interface with Windows Forms in C# for trains
- Another Android app pulling announcement from the aformentioned service

ABECEDAIRE/Software developer(Internship)

January 2019 to Febuary 2019, ROUEN (France)

Web development with JS, JQuery, HTML, CSS and SQL

 $\textbf{IDEA Informatique/} Software \ developer(Internship)$

June 2018 to July 2018, EVREUX (France)

Development of an ERP's features with PL-SQL and Delphi on Embarcadero, using TortoiseSVN as a SVN.